A Guide to the Lakeland High School Military Veterans Oral History Project, 1997 - 2007 [ongoing]
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lakeland High School Military Veterans Oral History Project, 1997-2007 [ongoing]
The Library of Virginia
41819
1.26 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Lakeland High School (Suffolk, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
For preservation purposes, patrons must use digital audio copies available on compact disc in place of all original audio cassette recordings.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Lakeland High School (Suffolk, Va.) history teacher India Meissel in multiple accessions.
Lakeland High School Military Veterans Oral History Project, 1997-2004 (Accession 41819). Received 7 March 2005.
Lakeland High School Military Veterans Oral History Project, 2004-2006 (Accession 42873). Received 10 October 2006.
Lakeland High School Military Veterans Oral History Project, 2006-2007 (Accession 43631). Received 20 February 2008.
Each new accession has been added to the original collection. THE COLLECTION IN ITS ENTIRETY IS FILED UNDER ACCESSION NUMBER 41819.
Alternative Form Available
Digital transfer (.WAV and .mp3 files) produced from original cassette audiotape in 2007 and 2008. These digital files have been placed on compact discs, which are used as service copies. Please note that some but not all of the interviews, 1997-2007, are available in audio or video form.
Historical Information
The Lakeland High School Military Veterans Oral History Project is a collection of interviews of veterans from the Suffolk, Virginia, area by Lakeland High School history students.
Scope and Content
The Military Veterans Oral History Project, which has been conducted annually from 1997-2007 [ongoing], captures veterans' recollections of military duty and their involvement in major U.S. military actions including World War II, the Korean War, the Vietnam War, and post-Vietnam conflicts. Written transcripts or reports are included for most interviews. Audio or video recordings are available for some but not all of the interviews. A complete list is available at the library. No materials are available from the 1998-1999 project.
Contents List
- Transcripts, 1997-2007., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 1-2)
  Transcripts from the Military Veterans Oral History Project, conducted annually from 1997-2007 [ongoing] by Lakeland High School (Suffolk, Va.) students. The interviews feature veterans recounting military experiences from the 1940's through the present.
  Arrangement: Chronological by project date.
  - "Suffolk Speaks: Memories of World War II," 1997-1998. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Reflections of War" (World War II, Vietnam, Persian Gulf), 1999-2000. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Salute to Veterans in Suffolk Public Schools" (veteran information sheets), 2000. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Answering the Call" (World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Persian Gulf), 2000-2001. (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - "In the Company of Heroes" (World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Persian Gulf), 2001-2002. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "In Times of Crisis" (World War II, Korea, Vietnam, post-Vietnam conflicts), 2002-2003. (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - "I Was Proud To Serve My Country" (World War II, Korea, Vietnam, post-Vietnam conflicts), 2003-2004. (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - "Duty, Honor, Courage" (World War II, Korea, Vietnam, Persian Gulf, Iraq, active duty), 2004-2005. (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Veterans Interview Project Clippings, 2004-2005. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "I got a letter from Uncle Sam" (World War II, Korea, Vietnam, post-Vietnam conflicts, Persian Gulf, active duty), 2005-2006. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "I always knew I wanted to serve in the military..." (World War II, Vietnam, post-Vietnam conflicts, Persian Gulf, Iraq, active duty), 2006-2007. (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
- Audio and video recordings, 1997-2007., Extent: 1 box. (Box 3)
  - Audio and video recordings of veteran interviews, 1997-2007. (Box 3)
    Please note that the collection does not include recordings for several of the interviews. Of the recordings present here, most are audio; only a handful are on video.